# Brandon Best

## **Software Engineer**

# Professional Summary

### **Brandon Best**

15 Queens Quay E Toronto, ON M5E 0A4

780.977.9925 bbest.dev@gmail.com

# Blended experience of exposure to software development in both a professional and entrepreneurial setting. Attained self-developed skills outside of academic path including machine learning, UI/UX design, and product management.

History of serial entrepreneurship in the industries of health, real estate, and collaboration tech. Currently pursuing a career in the fast paced world of startups to be on the forefront of innovation. Leadership and decades of teamwork experience through sports up to the collegiate level.

#### Skills

- Java, Python, JavaScript, and Bootstrap.
- Machine Learning engineering using Python with pandas, sklearn, Tensorflow, and Keras. Currently developing skills to specialize in Deep Learning techniques.
- React, Springframework, Google Firebase and Node.js.
- NoSQL and SQL databases and integrating with RESTful APIs
- Android mobile app development and OOP.
- UI/UX prototyping and design using Figma.

## **Experience**

#### Haemonetics / Fullstack Developer (Intern)

MAY 2019 - JUNE 2020, EDMONTON AB

Java web application developer using Springframework and Oracle SQL database. Large B2B product as a web application serving plasma donation centers around the globe as a Donor Management system.

#### **RBC** / Software Developer (Intern)

JAN 2018 - APR 2018, TORONTO ON

Developer for a new internal web application for Portfolio Managers. Worked on day zero data load scripts on the backend and frontend work done in Angular for UI improvements.

#### **Education**

#### **University of Alberta / Bachelor of Science**

SEPT 2013 - AUG 2019, EDMONTON AB

Majoring in Computing Science and a minor in Mathematics. Varsity Athlete on a scholarship for the football team.

#### Coursera / Deep Learning Specialization

JUNE 2020 - PRESENT, ONLINE

Online course provided by deeplearning.ai to specialize the deep learning techniques.

#### **UofA via Coursera** / Software Product Management

Specialization

OCT 2019 - DEC 2019, ONLINE

Online course to the practice of product management for software products.

#### **Activities**

#### Clinical Trial Watch / Creator

JUNE 2020, EDMONTON

Used an available API from Health Canada that had data on current clinical drug trials for COVID-19. Created this website using React and Bootstrap on the frontend. Node.js, Firebase Firestore, and Google Cloud Functions on the backend.

#### Ownable / Co-Founder

OCT 2019 - MAR 2020, TORONTO ON

Platform for fractional investment in real estate developments for the non-accredited investor. I led the product development using a paradigm from the Silicon Valley Product Group and designed the UI/UX prototype used in user testing. Also used React to create a landing website.

#### **Xpertz Software Corp /** Founder

MAY 2018 - JAN 2020, EDMONTON AB

Enterprise SaaS platform for skills management and collaboration analysis within large organizations. Did prototyping of MVP, contracted MVP to an outside developer, pitched to software companies for early adoption such as NeuroTechX and Shopify. Built a chat bot for Slack integration as well.

#### NeurAlbertaTech / VP Technology

FEB 2019 - APR 2019, EDMONTON AB

Co-founded a neurotechnology club at the University of Alberta to collaborate with students from neuroscience, psychology, and computing science to learn and build brain-computer interface projects.